Mss.B.H88
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Madame la comtesse, Oct. 21, 1838; 10x7-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. Social life and gossip in Paris. Old Call Number: B H88.9
  - Letter to Monsieur Powles, London, July 3, 1839; 10-1/2x8-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publication on geology by von Buch, hoping that the mining company and Degenhardt will find it useful. Old Call Number: B H88.32
  - Letter to ----, June 2, 1840; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Praises his work. Publication on soil formation is the best "Physical life history of the Earth." Old Call Number: B H88.93
  - Letter to "Madame", June 3, 1840; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Sorry they will not be visiting Berlin, and comments on the enjoyment the court received from their last visit. Old Call Number: B H88.80
  - Letter to Henri Milne-Edwards, 1840-1850?; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photostat of A.L.S. 5p. In French. Concerning electricity. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.9
  - Letter to ----, May 2, 1841; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.89
  - Letter to Friedrich Wilhelm IV, King of Prussia, August 19, 1841; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. Report to the King about political and scientific events.
  - Letter to Friedrich Wilhelm IV, King of Prussia, Aug. 24, 1841; 13-1/2x8-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning France and French affairs. Old Call Number: B H88.34
  - Letter to Jules Berger de Xivrey, Nov. 5, 1841; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Alexander von Humboldt, Aug., 1842; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
    New York. Photo. of A.L. 2p. and end. In French. Presents J. L. Stephens work on Central America. Concerning the publication. Old Call Number: B H88.1
  - Letter to Charles Brooks, June 22, 1842?; 8x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. (see Agassiz. Address... Humboldt, p.4.) Concerning a publication. Old Call Number: B H88a
  - Letter to Jules Berger de Xivrey, Feb. 18, 1843; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, June 23, 1843; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Refers to meeting with von Bülow. Old Call Number: B H88.97
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Dec. 10, 1843; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Concerning works on Egyptology. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.14
  - Letter to August Friedrich Pott, Jan. 28, 1844; 8-1/4x6; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Facsimile of A.L.S. 2p. In German. Concerning Gypsy language. Old Call Number: B H88.61
  - Letter to Richard Haight, June(?) 17, 1844; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin. Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Has not yet received the publication. Old Call Number: B H88.1
  - Letter to ----, April 3, 1846; 8x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin. A.L.S. 2p. In French. Recommends Waagen. Refers to Bülow. Old Call Number: B H88.46
  - Letter to Herr Lescow, Aug. 24, 1847; 9-1/2x8; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Sans Souci, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Concerning his large statue and hopes he will be recognized for it. Old Call Number: B H88.62
  - Letter to John L. Stephens, Sept. 21, 1847; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Does not feel worthy of having a stream ship named after him. From original in Bancroft library, University of California. (see Film 870.8) Old Call Number: B H88.25
  - Letter to ----, May 14, 1847; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning the appointment for a foreign diplomat. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.1
  - Letter to ----, Dec. 17, 1847; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Wishes to present to the king "the fine work you have published on my country" and wishes a note included for the king. Old Call Number: B H88.81
  - Letter to Monsieur Latronne, 1847; 9x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. with initials. 1p., end. In French. Concerning his publication on religious subject. Old Call Number: B H88.59 No.2
  - Letter to Monsieur Arago, Paris, Feb. 17, 1848; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Praises him for his work. Concerning illness and work. Refers to Portland, Littrow, Herschel, Brewster, Airy. Old Call Number: B H88.53
  - Letter to Louis Charles Galuski, Paris, Sept. 19, 1848; 10x8; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Sans Souci. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning his publication, Cosmos. Old Call Number: B H88.17
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 19, 1849; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Hopes that he will shortly be appointed to the Berlin university. Old Call Number: B H88.21
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, March 18, 1849; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Mentions Heinrich Brugsch. "My health is wonderfully preserved in the midst of these sad [political] events." Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.15
  - Letter to J.G. Flügel, Leipzig, Dec. 22, 1849; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin. Photostat of L. 2p. Copy. (from copy in U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.) Praises the New World and especially the work of the U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey. Old Call Number: B H88.5
  - Letter to Alexander Dunlop, London, April 10, 1850; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Concerning a canal at Panama and his comments on the best route for it. Old Call Number: B H88.110
  - Letter to John Charles Frémont, Oct. 7, 1850; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Sans Souci. Photostat of typed L. 2p. Advises him of the gold medal awarded him by Prussia. Is a member of the Berlin geographical society. Praises him. From original in Bancroft library, University of California. (see Film 870.8.) Old Call Number: B H88.26
  - Letter to Frau Geheimräthin Ernestine von Meusebach, Potsdam, Nov. 20, 1850; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Photostat of A.L.S. 4p. and add. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.4
  - Letter to Carl von Diebitsch, March 17, 1852; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. and add.envelope. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.20 no.1
  - Letter to François Magendie, May 17, 1851; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Introduces a young doctor, Dr. Mundt. Friendly letter. Old Call Number: B H88.43
  - Letter to Sir Henry Creswicke Rawlinson, Nov. 24, 1852; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Informs him that he is now created a Knight of the Royal Order of Merit for Sciences of Prussia. Esteems his work highly. Friendly letter. Old Call Number: B H88.76
  - Letter to George Ticknor, May 6, 1853; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, Photostat of L. 2p. Copy. In French. Concerning Bendan and asks help for him. On same sheet as letter from Ticknor to Lieber; Nov. 17, 1853. Old Call Number: B H88.24
  - Letter to Alexander von Humboldt, July 12, 1853; Tappan, Henry Philip, 1805-1881
    Berlin, Xerox of A.L.S. 4p., enc. wanting. Has come to Prussia to observe its system of education. Praises Humboldt as belonging to no one country but to mankind. Mentions his inaugural address as president of the University of Michigan. Refers to Jefferson, Madison and Gallatin.
  - Note to ----, Oct. 3, 1853; 4x7; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.N.S. 1p. (see Agassiz. Address...Humboldt, p.14.) He may have the specimen. Old Call Number: B H88a
  - Letter to ----, Oct. 22, 1853; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Old Call Number: B H88.64
  - Letter to Francis Lieber, Nov. 17, 1853; Ticknor, George, 1791-1871
    Berlin, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. with enc. of 2p. Encloses letter from Humboldt to Ticknor. Friendly letter. Praises Bendan. From original in H. E. Huntington Library. Old Call Number: B H88.24
  - Letter to Edmé Francois Jomard, March 21, 1854; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p., end. In French. Asks for publication on Aztec language On same sheet is reply from Jomard to Humboldt; April 6, 1854. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.16
  - Letter to Alexander von Humboldt, April 6, 1854; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Jomard, M., (Edmé François), 1777-1862
    A.L. 1p. In French. Forwards book on Aztec language to Buschmann. On same sheet as letter from Humboldt to Jomard; March 21, 1854. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.16
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, April 25, 1854; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 2p., end. In French. Praises his works on geography. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.17
  - Letter to [Christian Rauch?], Nov. 25, 1854; 8x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Friendly letter. Old Call Number: B H88.30
  - Letter to Bernhard Studer, January 25, 1855; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.101
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 14, 1855; 11x8-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Recommends Paul de Layarde for position as instructor. Names book written by de Layarde. Old Call Number: B H88.65
  - Letter to Jules Berger de Xivrey, Sep. 8, 1855; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Comtesse Lander(?), 1855?; 5x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L. in 3rd. P. 2p. In French. Concerning a publication on America. Old Call Number: B H88.15 no.4
  - Letter to William de la Rive, St. Petersburg, 1855?; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Charlottenbourg, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Hopes to visit him. Presents him with a copy of his Cosmos. Old Call Number: B H88.15 no.5
  - Letter to Carl von Diebitsch, Jan. 22, 1856; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. and add. envelope. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.20 no.2
  - Letter to Benecke and Wofferlein [Wesserlein?], March 20, 1856; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 2p. and envelope. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.87
  - Letter to Robert Brown [?], March 23, 1856; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. In French. (from original in British Museum, Natural history.) Friendly, complimentary letter. Old Call Number: B H88.16 no.1
  - Letter to ----, April 12, 1856; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 3p. In French. Concerning his Kosmos and Asie centrale Political news. Old Call Number: B H88.27
  - Letter to Mme Emme Gaggiotti-Richards, June (?)18, 1856; 8 1/4" x 5 1/2"; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. Mentions portrait painted by Mme Emma. [This portrait now hangs in the Corcoran Gallery, Washington, D.C. - 1957] Old Call Number: B H88.2
  - Letter to "Madame", Sept. 21, 1856; 8-1/2x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Friendly letter. Old Call Number: B H88.69
  - Letter to Johann Karl Eduard Buschmann, Aug. 3, 1857; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.20 no.5
  - Letter to ----, Sept., 1857; 7x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning translation and coloring by Galuski. Old Call Number: B H88.70
  - Letter to Lorin Blodget, Washington, Sept. 7, 1856; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. and add. with 1p. of translation, printed. Praises him on his publication on meterology. Old Call Number: B H88.1
  - Letter to Baron Feuillet de Conches, Paris, Dec. 15, 1857; 11x8-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Thanks for Legion of Honor conferred on him. Refers to famous French scientists, such as Arago and Laplace. Old Call Number: B H88.59 no.4
  - Letter to Alexander von Humboldt, April 14, 1857; 6-3/4x4-1/4; K ,A
    A.L.S. with initials. 1p. In German. Have elected him a member of the Berlinische Gesellschaft für Deutsche Sprache and wish to present to him his diploma. Old Call Number: B H88.59 No.3
  - Letter to Leonard Wollheim, 1858-1859?; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. and add. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.10
  - Letter to Charles R. Hale, March 12, 1859; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, Facsimile of A.L.S. 1p. In German with 1p.of English translation. Concerning publication of UP Philomathean society on Rosetta stone by C.R. Hale. Old Call Number: B H88.29
  - Obituary notice for Alexander von Humboldt, 1859; The Times(?)
    Photostat of D. 2p. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.18
  - Letter to Robert C. Waterston, Sept. 28, 1869?; 7-1/2x5; Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882
    Concord, A.L.S. 3p. (see Agassiz. Address...Humboldt, p.72.) Friendly letter. Refers to Humboldt. Printed: American Literature, vol.XLII, no.4, Jan. 1971, 546-8. Old Call Number: B H88a
  - u n d a t e d
  - Address delivered on the centennial anniversary of the birth of Alexander von Humboldt, Undated; 24 cm; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    under the auspices of the Boston Society of Natural History, by Louis Agassiz. Boston: Boston society of natural history, 1869. 107 p.: ill.; includes ms. items and engravings. I. Title. Old Call Number: B H88a
  - Concerning difficulties with American publishers of his works, Undated; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    D.S. 2p. In French. Old Call Number: B H88.33
  - Invitation to Dr. Wilson Fose, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.D. 1p. Old Call Number: B H88.113
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks if he has received Navier's publication. Old Call Number: B H88.67
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. In French. Introduces the chemist, Dr. Reich. Old Call Number: B H88.66
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday. A.L.S. 1p. In German. Hopes he has returned from Paris well and happy. Wants enclosed material and atlas sent to Bernard von Cotta. Old Call Number: B H88.58
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Tuesday. A.L.S. with initials. 2p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.7
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Wednesday evening. A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning Pickersgill's portraits of himself, Cuvier and Lafayette being shown in Paris. Old Call Number: B H88.56
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Thursday. A.L.S. 3p In French. Will visit Arago. Proposed changes in a "Essai Politique" after experiments with Gay Lussac. Old Call Number: B H88.71
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Jeudi [Thursday]. A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Invitation to dinner. Old Call Number: B H88.12
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Thursday. Photostat of A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French. Concerning volcanoes. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.7
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. In French. Refers to Lafayette and Tracy. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.12
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8-1/2x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Hopes to visit with them shortly. Old Call Number: B H88.48
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 3-3/4x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Asks that a reply be made at 5:30. Old Call Number: B H88.55
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. In French Incomplete. Refers to Mlle Williams and Delambre. Old Call Number: B H88.35
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8-1/2x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.13
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. In French. States his whereabouts for a few days. Old Call Number: B H88.11 no.6
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Lundi. A.L.S. 1p. Remarks on engravings; Tardieu doing a good job; will soon give to Poisson his work on the Orinoco river. Old Call Number: B H88.112
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning winds. Old Call Number: B H88.94
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Makes arrangements to meet with colleagues. Mentions de Werther and Arago; refers to the Institut. Old Call Number: B H88.107
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Potsdam, Friday. A.L.S. 1p. In German. Invitation to visit, with a friend. Old Call Number: B H88.82
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. A.L.S. 2p. In French. Asks for help on descriptions and identification of birds from Chile and elsewhere. Old Call Number: B H88.84
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.88
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning Klaproth. Chinese and Japanese knowledge of Straits of Magellan. Old Call Number: B H88.95
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. with initials. 3p. In French. Concerning a publication on the Mexican Indians. Old Call Number: B H88.86
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Fragment. Asks for funds for orphans. Old Call Number: B H88.75
  - Letter to ----, Undated; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. Writes over 2,000 letters each year and is, therefore remiss in correspondence. Busy with publications of Kosmos, etc. Politics. Old Call Number: B H88.52. March 19
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to ----, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to [M. l'Aine?], Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. In French. Wishes to keep instruments to show Berthollet and La Place. Desires his return date from Lyons. Old Call Number: B H88.91
  - Letter to P. H. (Pierre Hyacinthe) Azais, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to P. H. (Pierre Hyacinthe) Azais, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to P. H. (Pierre Hyacinthe) Azais, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Henry Washington Benham, Rome, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. ep., env., enc. wanting. In French. Old Call Number: B H88.108. January 14
  - Letter to Robert Brown, Soho Square, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Dimanche [Sunday]. Photostat of A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. and add., end. In French. Add: at Sir Joseph Banks. (from original in British Museum, natural history). Concerning some lines which Humboldt showed him. Old Call Number: B H88.16 no.2
  - Letter to Jacques Alexandre César Charles, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks him to befriend Houriet du Locke(?). Old Call Number: B H88.85
  - Letter to Jacques Alexandre César Charles, Undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Old Call Number: B H88.85
  - Letter to Athanase Laurent Charles Coqueral, Undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Names a person to whom the report should be made. Old Call Number: B H88.18
  - Letter to Monsieur Desnos, Undated; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Concerning volcanoes and Werner's theories. Old Call Number: B H88.51
  - Letter to Carl von Diebitsch, Undated; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. envelope. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.20 no.4 [Jan. 21]
  - Letter to Carl von Diebitsch, Undated; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. envelope. In German. Old Call Number: B H88.20 no.3. [Feb.10]
  - Letter to Sir William [?] Drummond, Undated; 5-1/2x6; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Tuesday. A.L.in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Complimentary letter. Refers to Gay-Lussac. Old Call Number: B H88.15 no.6
  - Letter to Professor Dubois, Undated; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning the shipment of art objects to Berlin. Old Call Number: B H88.59 no.5
  - Letter to M. Ducloseaux, Undated; 4-1/4x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks that a compatriot be allowed to see his "tombeau." Old Call Number: B H88.31
  - Letter to Mr. Theodore Sedgwick Fay, Undated; 8-3/4x5-1/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Will greet the three people and talk with them (one is a photographer). Presented by Whitfield Jenks Bell, Jr.; Sept. 1962. Old Call Number: B H88.45
  - Letter to Leonard Gay de Vernon (?), Undated; 5x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Gives directions. Old Call Number: B H88.15 no.7
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 8-1/2x6-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks him to see kotschouboi and present him a copy of his work on Egypt. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.27. Feb. 24
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 6-1/2x4-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Sunday, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Asks him to Speak on Egypt. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.24
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 8x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Sunday. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning his research. Old Call Number:B H88.4 no.18
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 5x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Tuesday. A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Invites him to meet Weddington. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.19
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p., end. and add. In French. Concerning his publication. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.26
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 4-3/4x3-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Thursday. A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Returns volume. Friendly letter. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.23
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 7-1/2x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Orders his work on Egypt. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.25
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 7x4-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks if his work has yet arrived. Old Call Number: B H88.4 no.22
  - Letter to Edmé François Jomard, Undated; 4-1/4x4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859